## **Liel Amar**

E-mailliel@lielamar.comDate of birthMarch 18th, 2001Websitelielamar.comMobile+972 (54) 974-1803GitHubgithub.com/LielAmarAddressGilo, Jerusalem

Expert developer with 7+ years of experience in a variety of languages, technologies, large-scale systems, applications, and games. A natural leader with proven capabilities in team management, public assistance, employee nurturing and tutoring, creating and executing work plans. Creative, inquisitive, and autodidact.

## **Professional Experience**

#### March 2015 - Current

#### **Software Developer** | Freelancer

- Developed React-based Web applications integrated with NoSQL & SQL databases.
- Developed public libraries in various languages, including Java & TypeScript.
- Founded & developed "Tsophen" A B2C Startup in the data protection field.
- Developing applications for clients using various frameworks, technologies and tools.

#### **January 2021 - August 2021**

## **Software Developer** | ReWrite Media, Remote

- Developed games, cosmetics, tools, and features for Minecraft Servers, using Minestom,
  Spigot & Velocity.
- Designed UI and implemented Web applications using Java's Spring Boot, NodeJS with Express & React, and Amazon Web Services.
- Integrated Redis and MongoDB with a Message-Broker, using RabbitMQ.
- Worked in a team and collaborated with other employees on a daily basis.

#### August 2019 - April 2020

#### **Developer, Unit Co-Founder and Leader** | Israel Defense Forces, Israel

- Designed, implemented, tested, deployed, and maintained a real-time location-based Web application and multiple desktop applications.
- Provided units with evaluations, demonstrations, and samples.
- Recruited, trained, and commanded soldiers, pushed their personal development.
- Collaborated with other brigades, shared resources, and knowledge.

#### July 2017 - July 2019

### **Developer, Video Editor** | Oversight, Israel

- Managed and maintained 20 Spigot servers on Linux and Windows machines.
- Designed and developed 7 large-scale Minecraft minigames.
- Led weekly development meetings and monthly meetings with the volunteer team.

## **Volunteer Positions**

July 2019 - May 2021

## **Staff Member, Mentor** | Hypixel

- Provided in-game assistance to players and general moderation.
- Trained and mentored new staff members.
- Found bugs and tested new updates, features, and minigames.

#### July 2016 - July 2019

## Server Manager, Developer | Play-IL, Israel

- Recruited, trained, and guided new and old staff members.
- Developed new minigames, released updates, patched bugs, and exploits.
- Led weekly work meetings and monthly community events.

# **Education and Languages**

October 2021 - July 2024

**Bachelor's in Computer Science** | The Hebrew University of Jerusalem GPA: 95/100

## September 2016- June 2019

High-School | Ort's College

Finished with emphasis on Computer Science & Physics

Hebrew - Native language

English - Fluent speaker